# **SOHAM DUTTA**

#### FRONT END DEVELOPER

917-855-9843
--------------

xzoham@gmail.com

Brooklyn, NY

https://www.sohamdutta.com

https://github.com/SohamDutta1216

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/soham-dutta-ny

## BIO

Front End / Web Developer with 3+ years of experience. Experienced in working with a team to design, develop, test, and deliver pixel perfect and responsive web applications on a deadline. I enjoy solving problems and finding new ways to optimize performance.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

# Front End Developer at ServiceTitan • 01/2022 - 12/2023

- **Pixel-Perfect and Responsive Component Development:** Produced pixel-perfect and responsive React components based on Adobe XD designs, achieving a 100% match rate over the course of multiple sprints.
- **Migrated CMS from Kentico to Strapi:** Led the successful migration of over 2000 client websites from Kentico (A paid CMS) to Strapi (A free open source CMS), resulting in a 100% reduction in content management system costs and resulting in a substantial improvement in content editing efficiency.
- **Developed a clean and scaleable GraphQL API architecture:** Developed scaleable GraphQL queries in conjunction with a headless CMS (Strapi).
- **Automated Manual Processes:** Developed and implemented scripts that automated manual processes, saving an estimated 100 work hours per month. The scripts handled the migration of clients content from one CMS to another.
- **Debugged Issues in Existing Codebase:** Resolved 800+ bugs in the existing codebase while maintaining a 24 hour turnaround on tickets.

## Front End Developer at FieldRoutes • 06/2021 - 01/2022

- **Developed Scalable Templating Software:** Engineered a templating software with over 50 different themes resulting in a 30% decrease in website deployment time, enabling clients to launch fully customized websites within 48 hours. This included the development of hundreds of scaleable and responsive React Components This software led to our company eventually being acquired by ServiceTitan; A leader in CRM software.
- **Overhauled Legacy Code Base:** Led the migration of a 10-year-old legacy code base to a modern stack React, Gatsby, GraphQL, Node, and SASS, reducing load times by 40% and improving overall site performance.
- Mentored Colleagues in JavaScript and React: Aided in the learning of JavaScript and React for my colleagues and senior engineers as one of the first developers on the team with React experience.
- Researched and Implemented Emerging Technologies: Introduced and implemented Typescript, SASS, and
  Custom React Hooks into our existing codebase resulting in a 30% improvement in application performance and user
  experience.
- **Developed a clean and scaleable GraphQL API architecture:** Developed scaleable GraphQL queries in conjunction with a headless CMS (Kentico).

## Junior Front End Developer at FieldRoutes • 01/2021 - 06/2022

- **Debugged Issues in Existing Codebase:** Resolved 300+ bugs in the existing codebase while maintaining a 48 hour turnaround on tickets.
- **Executed Software Build and Release Processes:** Helped architect a streamlined build and release pipeline, reducing deployment time by 25% and increasing deployment frequency by 50%.
- **Wrote Technical Documentation:** Authored comprehensive technical documentation covering system architecture and development processes.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

LANGUAGES: Javascript | Typescript | HTML5 | CSS3 | GraphQL

FRAMEWORKS & LIBRARIES: React.js | GatsbyJS | Redux | Axios | Node.js | SocketIO | Jest

OTHER TECHNOLOGIES & CONCEPTS: Responsive Design | Cross Browser Compatibility | Rest API | React

Custom Hooks | Context API | MongoDB | PostgreSQL | AWS | Jira | Git | Adobe XD | Figma | ThreeJS

#### EDUCATION

**Long Island University**